"HEARTS ARE MADE TO BE BROKEN."
OSCAR WILDE
-So this is your palace?
-It’s more like my museum.
I love your house.
It was my grandfather’s.
He built it.
-Have you always lived here?
-All my life.
This house is as much mine
as I am its.
-Does it work?
-What?
Saying those grandiose phrases
to hook up.
"This house is as much mine
as I am its".
No. I’m serious.
Years ago. my grandfather’s family
owned almost all this area.
When my parents died.
I got the house.
and my sisters got everything else.
-Guess how long it took to sell it all.
-Ten minutes?
-Not that long.
-And they made a fortune.
No. A mega-fortune.
The house is impressive.
but maybe you lost out.
I’m not interested in money.
I care more about my daughters.
my work. Money is...
boring.
A little money is boring.
Is it real?
Everything in this house is real.
-Do you know Eric Clapton?
-Yes.
but Miguel Ríos gave me that guitar.
Are you friends?
I produced
Rock en el País de las Maravillas.
A good album.
Did you make a mega-fortune?
No. just a fortune.
That tree
is my favorite place in the house.
I gave my first kiss of love there.
And what was it like?
Was it something like this?
My grandfather always told me
that it was a magic tree
and long ago this was a sacred forest
and nymphs. spirits and witches
lived in its trees.
How interesting.
and I’m sure it was
a fantastic place for fucking.
THE HANGED WOMAN
No. she wasn’t my girlfriend.
We saw each other occasionally.
-How long did the relationship last?
-It wasn’t a relationship.
It was just sex.
And it was a few months.
What were you? Fuck buddies?
She was a singer-songwriter.
We ended it a month ago.
but she insisted on carrying on.
So you left her.
I stopped answering her messages.
She kept insisting. so I told her
I was seeing someone else now.
Her?
No. I met her tonight.
-Did you come straight from the concert?
-Yes. we did.
Did you know the victim?
I have no idea who she is.
It’s my first time in this house.
Since what time have you been with him?
Well. all evening.
-Was there anyone else in the house?
-No. just the two of us.
My daughters are with their mother.
We have shared custody.
I never play at home
when they’re with me.
Playing at home.
You know what I mean.
-Did your daughters know her?
-No. they’re 9 and 15 years old.
Honestly. I’d prefer
if they knew nothing about this.
You are
very considerate.
So was she. hanging herself
when they weren’t here.
Imagine if they’d found her.
Well. you’ll have to look after him.
Of course I will.
And I’ll introduce him to dad.
-Bye. Mom!
-Bye.
-Hello. girls.
-Hello!
Hello. Dad!
And this canary?
It’s a nightingale
and I’m looking after him.
It’s a lovely nightingale.
Where did he come from?
Patti found it injured in the forest.
Why didn’t you bring Marley?
Because he’s my dog
and his custody isn’t shared.
Stay for supper.
I’ve ordered sushi from Rashomon.
I’m not hungry.
It’s your favorite restaurant.
Not anymore.
And I don’t like them
spending time in this house.
This house is their house.
Don’t bring women when they’re here.
You know I never do.
You never play at home. right?
Who told you that?
The police.
Did you think
they wouldn’t talk to me?
I’m amazed they didn’t
interrogate the children.
Fuck whoever you want!
Like when we were married.
but they can’t kill themselves
in the garden where my children play.
Pretty. so pretty. my beautiful Oscar.
Pretty. so pretty. my gentle Oscar.
Fly sweetly.
Fly blue.
-How’s the cake?
-Delicious.
-Did you make it?
-Of course.
-You’re lying to us.
Dad...
Do you know who Rebeca is?
Rebeca? I have no idea.
I found this on the couch.
And look. it says Rebeca.
Give me that.
-She’s your girlfriend.
-No.
She’s one of them.
And you two?
Have you got boyfriends?
Janis does!
Shut up!
-His name is Dani.
-Patti!
-What Dani is that?
-He’s nobody.
-Is she lying to us?
-Of course.
I don’t have a boyfriend.
OK. OK. I’ll be quiet.
Is it Daniel Reyes?
-Our neighbor across the way.
-How do you know?
A little bird told me.
Tweet tweet.
Is he called Oscar?
Who’s Oscar? Patti’s boyfriend?
-No.
-Her parrot.
-He’s a nightingale.
-Your boyfriend is a nightingale?
-Yes.
-She’s even written a song about him.
I have the words. but not the music.
Heavens.
But what a coincidence!
A piano!
-Shall I help you?
-Come on!
-OK?
-OK.
OK?
-Pretty. so pretty...
-Again.
Pretty. so pretty. my beautiful Oscar.
Pretty. so pretty. my gentle Oscar.
Janis. the guitar.
Pretty. so pretty. my beautiful Oscar.
Pretty. so pretty. my gentle...
Oscar!
Janis. don’t open the door!
Janis. Janis!
Oscar!
Don’t worry. sweetheart.
He’ll be in the garden.
sleeping in the tree
or in the rose garden.
We’ll look for him in daylight
and I’m sure we’ll find him.
What if he’s gone?
He was injured. I don’t think
he could have flown over the wall.
What if a cat ate him?
Oscar looks pretty smart.
If we haven’t found him.
a cat won’t catch him.
Maybe he’s playing hide and seek.
Dad.
you know that nightingales
don’t do that.
You’ll see.
tomorrow he’ll sing you awake.
-Are you lying?
-No.
Tomorrow we’ll find him
and I’ll help you cure him.
OK? Now go to sleep.
Oscar!
Oscar?
Oscar. come down here.
Come on.
You’re never to escape again.
Hello.
Dad!
Patti!
What are you doing there?
I climbed up for Oscar.
Come down. please.
You climbed a tree at night?
You could have fallen
and killed yourself.
And goodbye. vacation.
There was a lady in the tree.
but she isn’t there now.
Patti. it was a dream.
another one of your dreams.
Janis. you and I are the only ones here.
She’d hurt her neck.
Don’t worry. Dad. last week
she dreamed I shot myself in the head.
And I’d just got extensions!
OK. I see that you don’t believe me.
-Patti!
-I’m going to play with Oscar.
-Why did you tell her?
-Tell her what?
What your mother told you
when she shouldn’t have.
Mom didn’t tell me anything.
Janis. please.
Dad. what happened?
Dad?
Ana. don’t deny it.
Patti said she saw a lady in the tree
with a wound on her neck.
It’s obvious you told them.
It must be another one of her nightmares.
Yes. but that nightmare is based
on something you told them.
I didn’t tell them anything.
Then they heard you telling someone.
I’ve only spoken to the police.
but they weren’t in the house.
If she has another nightmare
we’ll take her to her psychologist..
And you should go back to yours.
Don’t worry. I usually do
every time I talk to you.
Patti.
Dani told me that two weeks ago
a woman hanged herself in that tree.
One of Dad’s girlfriends.
Her name was Rosa Martín.
but she called herself The Hanged Woman.
My mother filmed this.
I got it off her phone.
She saw her going in several times.
Well. her and lots of others.
Dad needs a psychiatrist.
What?
Is this the woman you saw in the tree?
Yes.
Yes. it’s her.
What the hell is that?
Wait a minute.
I won’t be long.
Pretty. so pretty.
you’re a nuisance. Oscar.
Fran.
Fran!
Fran?
Look at me.
Oscar!
What the hell have you done?
Hello. Dad!
-Hi! Did you have a good time?
-Where’s Oscar?
Sweetheart. I have to tell you something
that will make you a bit sad.
I got up this morning
and the poor bird...
He isn’t a bird.
he’s a nightingale!
He was hurt and you promised
to look after him!
-Now he’s dead and it’s your fault!
-I know. love. but...
Leave me alone!
Maybe we can bury him
in the rose garden.
Who were you with last night. Dad?
I took him out to the porch a moment
for some air
and this morning I found him like this.
You left him out there all night?
Was he such a nuisance?
-I’m not surprised Mom left.
-Look. Janis...
Janis. please.
Don’t be scared.
I just want to be your friend.
Your name is...
Patti. isn’t it?
And you can see me.
No one can see me
if I don’t want them to.
When I was your age I was like you.
So I guess we’re both special.
don’t you think?
Who are you?
What happened to your nightingale?
What happened to Oscar?
How do you know his name is Oscar?
I hear you calling him.
and singing to him.
I called him Oscar for Oscar Wilde.
For The Nightingale and the Rose?
-It’s my favorite story.
-Mine too.
But
I always cry when the nightingale dies.
Now they’ll tell me that Oscar is fine
and that he’ll live happily
in the heaven for birds.
What if we bring him back?
How?
With magic.
With my magic.
You’re a ghost. aren’t you?
I’m your guardian ghost.
How do we do it?
The magic that would revive Oscar
can only be done from inside the house.
Going in there will give me that power.
Will you let me go in?
Have I your permission?
When?
Soon.
Very soon.
Patti.
wake up.
It’s time.
It has to be now.
-Is it the time Oscar died?
-It’s the time I died.
-What are we going to do?
-Sing.
Pretty. so pretty. my beautiful Oscar.
Pretty. so pretty. my gentle Oscar.
Come back to Patti. come back to me.
I am your rose of thorns.
I am your rose of bile.
Close your eyes.
Pretty. so pretty. my beautiful Oscar.
Pretty. so pretty. my gentle Oscar.
Fly softly.
Patti?
Look. Dad!
Oscar wasn’t dead. he was sleeping!
And he won’t escape again!
Fly!
Why doesn’t the bird escape?
He won’t leave.
She told me he’d stay here forever.
She?
The woman who cured him.
The woman who hanged herself?
Yes.
How did she cure him?
Janis. I can’t tell you.
Why?
-Is it a secret?
-Yes.
And as well. you’d be scared.
-Aren’t you afraid?
-No.
She’s my friend.
She’s teaching me to do magic.
how to enter dreams.
She is our guardian ghost.
Look at her.
Is she here now?
No.
Where is she?
You’ve got something inside you.
if you don’t stop running away
I’m going to leave you
and I won’t come back.
You have a lovely voice.
I know. because I want to kiss you.
Do you always kiss your artists?
Only when I find them irresistible.
I really like you. but...
I don’t want you to break my heart.
Don’t worry.
Those of us with broken hearts
don’t break the hearts of others.
-Was your heart broken?
-No. but it was shattered.
I’m scared I’ll cut myself
on the splinters.
And if we continue this conversation
in my bedroom?
If we’re going to make love.
I prefer to do it in the garden.
under your tree.
DELETING FILES...
Fuck. Ana!
I’m sorry!
I’m sorry.
Patti let me in.
Patti let you in?
Yes.
to take care of you.
Don’t you want me to?
I’m going to take care of you.
Is it a good time to tell you I love you?
No.
It’s the worst time.
You know what?
There hasn’t been a single day
when I haven’t missed you.
Sure.
I haven’t missed you.
And that’s why you’re here.
I’m here because I felt like fucking.
And you’re an easy lay.
we all know that.
Well. what’ll we tell the girls tomorrow?
I won’t be here tomorrow.
I’m not sleeping here.
Well. then?
What was this?
I’m like you.
I like playing.
Is that what it was? A game?
You don’t need me.
And what do you think I need?
A lesson.
Who’ll teach it to me?
-You?
-Me!
What did you think?
That I would go silently?
With my mouth shut?
Without protesting.
without bothering you?
Without upsetting your life
one fucking little bit?
That I’d disappear
like I’d never existed?
I’ve got bad news for you. Fran.
you won’t be able to delete me!
Dad!
I’m sorry. my love. it was a nightmare.
Are you all right?
No!
I made her believe
I could fall in love with her.
but I just wanted to fuck.
It's possible that
if she hadn't killed herself.
you could have fallen in love with her.
Guilt is destroying you
as if you were her killer.
and you didn’t kill her.
or want her to die.
In the dream.
she strangles you with the rope
she used to kill herself.
It was her decision.
That’s what your conscious tells you.
It wasn’t your fault.
My daughters are obsessed with her too.
Especially Patti.
Patti adores you.
She sees you suffering
and she wants to share it with you.
even take on the burden.
It’s very common.
She should never have heard
about what happened.
Or maybe yes.
Why hide the truth?
Children are stronger than they seem.
Unless a bird dies on them.
-That bird wasn’t dead.
-I saw it dead.
Well. obviously it wasn’t dead.
it was asleep. or catatonic.
Or drunk.
Fran.
someone has died.
and you’re all somatizing it
because you have feelings
you don’t know how to handle.
That woman did something
very violent against you.
against your family.
and against your house.
Janis?
Stop. you’re going to kill him!
Grab everything. we're out of here!
Dad. what’s happening?
Patti. run!
Grab her!
Shut up!
Janis. Janis. help!
Help!
Let me go!
-Help!
-Shut up!
-Just shut up!
Shut your mouth!
Shut your fucking mouth!
Shut the fuck up!
Look at me.
10. Calle del Olmo. please!
No. don’t kill her! Don’t kill her!
I told you. I’m your guardian ghost.
Patti!
Run. come on!
Where are my daughters?
Patti?
-Mom!
-Janis!
Where’s Fran? Where’s your father?
-I don’t know.
-They took him away.
What? Where?
Don’t worry. it’s all over.
-Your ex-husband has concussion.
-What?
But he’s conscious.
We sent him to the hospital
to be checked.
Your daughters got a fright.
and little more.
Really it was the attackers
who came off worst.
What do you mean?
They’re both badly injured.
and what’s more. someone brutalized them.
Who? Fran?
Your family was lucky.
Yes. I’m fine. it was just a knock.
When are you coming back?
Mom says next week.
for your birthday and Janis’.
And we’re bringing Marley!
Put your mother on. please.
Mom. Dad wants to speak to you.
How are you?
I’m perfectly fine.
Why don’t you send the girls now?
Because they were scared to death?
Remember. this is my week.
In case you haven’t realized.
you put their lives in danger.
Don’t worry. I’ve installed
the best security system there is.
Fran. your life is chaos. and I don’t
want that chaos for my daughters.
So. next week then.
You can come to my party if you like.
Fran. you and I have
got nothing to celebrate.
At first I didn’t recognize her.
but then I realized
your attacker was Sofía Muñoz.
the woman you brought here
the night Rosa Martín hanged herself.
I don’t want to bruise your ego.
but I think she hooked up with you
to get into your house
and see if you had anything of value.
You know.
Sofía doesn’t remember
anything that happened.
but she has cervical fractures.
She was nearly strangled.
You think it was me?
No. we questioned them
and we know it wasn’t you.
Then there’s the other guy.
His face is destroyed.
And your daughters didn't do that.
Well. then?
Was there anyone else in the house?
No.
Do you have any animals?
Just a nightingale.
I think we can rule out
the nightingale.
Hey!
Marley?
What’s wrong? Come here.
Come with me.
I’ve rung you several times.
I’m sorry.
These last days have been
very complicated.
I just wondered how you were
after the attack.
I’m fine. don’t worry.
I’ve come to tell you that it’s over.
This isn’t a good time.
Fran. it’s all right.
It was fun and that’s it.
It’s just that I hoped
you’d be more honest.
Listen...
You’re being a nuisance.
I think we should still be friends.
more than anything
because our children are dating.
Really. can we talk about this
another time?
Fran. relax.
Go back to your party.
They’re bringing out the cake.
For he’s a jolly good fellow.
for he’s a jolly good fellow.
and so say all of us.
My girls!
And so say all of us!
For Janis!
Darling. you have everything
you need to be happy.
Youth.
beauty.
talent.
and...
love.
And for Fran. who also has
everything necessary to be happy.
But it isn’t enough.
He always wants more.
More youth.
more beauty.
Talent isn’t so important.
But love...
Love is.
Or is it sex?
Silvia. please...
Is now a good time to talk about this?
I know what you’re all thinking.
That I’m another of his lovers.
It’s possible.
But don’t worry. Fran.
I won’t hang myself from a tree.
It hurts too much.
It hurts forever.
And I still have a lot to say
about you. Fran.
We all still have a lot to say
about you.
Fran.
Here.
What happened?
Mind the glass...
Marley...
You’re all wet.
Were you swimming?
Patti?
What’s wrong?
You’re soaking wet.
I have to tell you something
that will make you very sad.
Patti believes
that the woman who hanged herself
in the garden
is a ghost who lives in the house.
She cured her bird.
she saved us from the thieves.
she bewitched Silvia.
and she killed Marley
because his barking broke her spell.
And the worst thing is
that now Janis believes it too.
Traumatic events generate energies
that can provoke
situations of collective hysteria.
but at times that can be reversed.
How?
I know people
who cleanse those energies.
Witches?
Parapsychologists.
I don’t really believe in those things.
Patti does.
She killed Marley.
She’s hiding somewhere.
We have to throw her out of here.
And I think I know how to do it.
She taught me.
We have to use blood and fire.
We need things of hers
to burn them.
Dani.
We have to burn everything.
Give it to me.
I’ve made a doll that looks like her.
Between the three of us.
we can make her go away.
Rosa?
Are you there?
We want to talk to you.
You are hurting me.
And you hurt my mother.
And Marley.
Marley drowned.
No.
No. you killed him.
Why?
Why did you kill Marley?
Why did you kill Oscar?
Leave this house!
Go away!
Go away now!
Stop.
Go in.
Dani!
Dani. are you all right?
Dad. he needs to go to hospital!
Don’t take this badly. but all this
looks to me like science fiction.
I told Dr. Durán
I don’t believe in ghosts.
But you do believe in physics.
In energies.
Traumatic events have happened here.
-What are you going to do exactly?
-Well. however odd it may seem.
we’re going to try to reverse
the residual psychic energy
left by those events.
I hope it reassures my daughters.
They’re obsessed by what’s happened.
especially the little one.
Patti. right?
Her name is Patti.
-And you are...?
-May I walk through your garden?
Hello.
I’m Begoña.
Can you see me?
Yes. I’ve always been able
to see those like you.
The dead. you mean?
I prefer to call you persons in transit.
Right.
But I’m not in transit.
I live here.
You killed yourself here.
You should leave.
That would be best
for everyone. wouldn’t it?
Especially for you.
And where should I go?
To Heaven. to Hell?
You’re causing a lot of pain.
They caused me pain too.
What’s she doing?
At times we work with her.
She’s a very powerful medium.
We’re lucky to have her here.
She’s going to Africa tomorrow.
I think you don’t even know
if you love him or hate him.
Is there a difference?
I’ve seen other cases like yours.
The longer you’re here.
the more you’ll lose touch with reality.
Soon only your obsession will be left.
That obsession
which destroyed your life
will end up destroying your soul.
My soul...
Why don’t you worry about yours?
You hanged yourself here.
It must have hurt a lot.
Have you seen my death?
You have to leave.
I can help you transition. trust me.
You know what?
I want to see yours too.
Don’t look him in the eye.
Our blood is stronger than yours.
Shangó. I invoke the name of Shangó!
I am the God of Thunder.
I am Thunder.
Leave.
Leave!
This is my axe!
I am Fire. I am Lightning. I am Shangó!
Shangó's axe is hitting you!
No. no!
It seems you’re going to die in Africa.
Perhaps. but I must help a child.
Let me help you.
I’m not leaving this house
and you can’t make me.
I supposed you’d say that.
I’ve drawn a circle of blood around you.
Now my blood ties you to this tree.
You want to stay?
All right. stay.
But I won’t let you do more harm.
You killed yourself on the tree
and you’ll live in the tree.
Don’t worry.
She isn’t here anymore.
All that was a year ago.
I remember it
as a nightmare we all had.
but it ended.
Patti doesn’t see ghosts.
Janis and Dani are still dating.
they saved his eye.
Well. it seems the parapsychologists
did the trick.
They told me that the medium
died a few days later
on a humanitarian mission in Africa.
Are you still going to therapy?
Twice a week.
I’ve learned a lot.
I’ve regretted a lot.
The girls have told me
that recently you’re a model dad.
Great. because I asked them
to use that expression.
They told me that too.
Is that the same swing?
The same one you swung on
when you were a child.
Heavens.
And when did it break?
May 13. 1997.
The day I turned 16.
The day we kissed for the first time.
I don’t remember.
Are you lying?
Of course.
You leaned on the tree.
I went over
and I kissed you.
Well. it isn’t our tree anymore.
Yes. it is.
And so is the house.
I wouldn’t live there again.
Then we’ll sell it.
What?
If I’ve learned anything about you.
it’s that your life is meaningless
without that house.
If I’ve learned anything about me.
it’s that my life is meaningless
without you.
Aren’t you going a bit fast?
You’re right. we’ve only known
each other for forty years.
Why don’t you stay for supper
and we’ll get better acquainted?
I know it no longer matters
about the questions that I failed
and when I try to correct myself
you won’t be there.
I know that you don’t care
if I can no longer breathe.
and if I choke
I know that you won’t save me.
You have something within you.
I have seen it shine.
but you run away.
Miss me.
don’t fail me this time.
because I don’t know if I’ll be back.
-Is Mom going to stay?
-I hope so.
Forever?
I hope so.
She doesn’t want to live here.
You know what?
I’ve decided to sell this house
and buy a nicer one.
Do you think it’s a good idea?
It could be a good idea.
Oscar?
Patti...
Don’t be scared. you’re dreaming.
We’re both dreaming.
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
Just to apologize.
I never wanted to hurt you. really.
I loved your father.
I loved him from
the moment I saw him.
Remember The Nightingale and the Rose?
The nightingale says
that love is better than life.
that his wings are flame-colored.
and his body is colored like flame.
his lips are sweet as honey
and his breath is like frankincense.
I was mistaken.
I thought that my love for your father
was a mutual love.
That his heart froze
when your mother left and I could cure it.
Silly. wasn’t I?
And now you’ll be
a happy family again. Patti.
I know that soon you’ll sell the house
and move away.
I don’t want to be trapped in the tree.
In the tree?
A year ago.
a witch left me
shut away in the tree.
But I want to get out of here!
You have to help me. please.
But I don’t know how!
Touch the mirror.
You have to do what she did.
but in reverse.
Only that will break the spell.
I am your rose of sugar
I am your rose of honey.
What would you like for breakfast?
The usual.
Look at me.
Ana!
Dad?
No!
-Dad?
-No!
What’s wrong?
It’s your mother!
Mom!
Mom. Mom!
Patti!
Hurry. hurry!
No. no!
No!
I was keen to finally meet you.
Fran talks a lot about you.
-Does he?
-Yes.
How did you meet Fran?
He came to one
of my first concerts when...
Well. I was still nobody and
I think we fell in love instantly.
That night we made love under the tree.
under his tree.
and a month later I was living here.
Then we got married. and here we are.
They were very happy years.
And productive too?
-Yes. Fran produces all my albums.
-He only produces your albums.
-I think that’s more than enough.
-Yes. yes.
So.
why don’t you tell me
about those dreams?
The dreams.
Well. they started a few days ago.
I dream that I’m in love with Fran.
But...
He doesn’t love you back?
Exactly.
He ignores me.
And
that sends me into a deep depression
and makes me
kill myself. I hang myself.
And my ghost stays in the house
and I make life impossible for everyone.
For Fran.
for his daughters who.
really. I love as if they were my own.
for Marley. the dog.
Last night. I dreamed that I killed Ana.
his ex. but we’re close friends.
She’s like a sister for me.
And
does anyone else appear in your dreams?
Yes. a woman appears.
she sneaks into the house.
Who is she?
I don’t know.
I don’t know. I can’t see her face.
It’s covered. she’s wearing...
It’s an African mask.
Like that one?
Not like it.
it is that one.
Interesting.
It’s a ceremonial mask
made to fight against evil beings.
Did you know that?
I’m sorry. but I’d completely
forgotten about that album.
Who is she?
Is she a thief?
A fan. perhaps?
I don’t think she’s a fan because
she doesn’t want to talk to me.
just to him.
What does she say to him?
I don’t know.
As soon as she sees me she runs off.
And then I chase her and chase her
and I can’t catch her.
She goes into the house
and it seems I’ll catch her
but she locks herself in Patti’s room.
What happens when you go in?
I can’t go into Patti’s room.
Why?
I don’t know. I can’t.
-Patti doesn’t let you.
-I can’t.
Are you sure no one else
appears in your dreams?
There’s a man too. an elderly man.
who is always in the shadows.
He seems harmless.
but I know he isn’t.
I don’t trust him.
He scares me.
And I don’t want him near Fran.
Why?
Because he wants to kill Fran.
He wants to kill Fran.
Go away!
Rosa.
I’m very sorry.
I’m not an expert in dreams.
Maybe you should speak
to another therapist.
What?
You should see another therapist...
Then why have you come?
Don’t you remember?
I’m the psychologist at Patti’s school.
She told me about your dreams
and she’s very worried.
I thought it would be
a good idea to talk...
Forgive me.
I’m sorry.
I don’t know
how I could have lost my mind like that.
Don’t worry.
I must be a bit...
Between sleeping badly.
organizing Fran’s party.
and I’m composing a song. you know.
Heavens!
Are you going to sing?
So it seems.
You know.
I have a friend who’s a big fan of yours.
Why are you here on your own?
Your birthday present.
Is it a song?
No. Me. sing?
How long since I told you I love you?
-Not since this morning.
-Too long.
I love you.
I’ll see what Marley wants.
He’s being a nuisance.
The cake’s ready.
Does your father know?
-Please. we’re professionals.
-You followed my recipe?
-Word by word.
-And it’s amazing.
Most important.
is it very. very. well hidden?
-In my room.
-Where no one can enter!
OK. here’s the plan.
In the middle of the party
I’ll sing my song.
when I finish. you turn off the lights
and bring out the cake.
-OK?
-Perfect.
OK. come on.
Thank you for being
the best stepmother in the world.
No. it’s easy when you have
the best stepdaughters in the world.
You don’t say anything now
and I just want to scream.
without wanting to. I’m letting you fly.
It’s a bit late for stirring up blood
and I forgot how to stop
a long time ago.
You have something within you.
I have seen it shine.
but you run away
and run away.
Miss me.
don’t fail me this time.
because I don’t know if I’ll be back.
You have something within you.
if you don’t stop running away
I’m going to leave you
and I won’t come back.
Bravo! Bravo!
Hey. I didn’t see you!
When did you get here?
Just in time to see you sing.
I’ll introduce you.
-Your biggest fan.
-Thank you for inviting us.
You were wonderful.
Thank you for coming.
Your face looks familiar.
Have we met?
I was here a long time ago.
investigating a case of suicide.
I didn’t tell you.
my friend is a policeman.
You mean a case of suicide
in this house?
Yes. a woman hanged herself on that tree.
A messy love affair.
It’s time for the cake.
For he’s a jolly good fellow.
for he’s a jolly good fellow.
and so say all of us!
And so say all of us.
Thank you!
Hey.
the cake is delicious.
Thank you.
-Did you make it?
-Of course.
-You’re lying to us.
-Of course!
Come on. I want to tell you something.
Come on.
Tell me.
That man. the policeman.
he asked me things about you.
About me?
When?
Fifteen years ago.
That’s impossible.
He wanted to know if I knew you.
and how you were getting on with Dad.
Child. fifteen years ago
you still hadn’t been born.
Rosa! You’re missing
the best of the party!
We’re going to drink a toast!
Where did you get that mask. Patti?
Patti?
So someone killed themself here.
Fifteen years ago.
Don’t you remember?
It’s true.
I’d forgotten.
A woman killed herself here.
A woman?
What woman?
Who?
It was you.
You hanged yourself on the tree.
Did you tell them my dream?
It wasn’t a dream.
Isn’t that right. Ana?
For the great Rosa Martín.
also known as "The Hanged Woman".
who. doing honor to her stage name.
hanged herself from that beautiful tree
fifteen years ago
and then contrived to murder me
in the same way.
For the Hanged Woman!
This is a joke. isn’t it?
What kind of fucking joke is this?
Fran?
I didn’t kill anybody. Fran.
Yes. you did.
You killed yourself.
you killed Oscar. Marley.
and you killed Ana too!
But Ana is there!
And Marley!
Don’t you hear Marley barking?
Marley? Marley?
Fran. it wasn’t me.
Fran. it wasn’t me!
This isn’t happening.
Go away!
Don’t be scared.
You’re dreaming. we’re both dreaming.
Come on. run!
-Where are we going?
-To my room.
Run!
-It’s time.
-It has to be now.
It’s almost the time she died.
Run. open the door!
I can’t.
You have the key in your hand.
Patti!
Who are you?
You aren’t Patti’s psychologist.
No.
I am Patti.
Patti is a child.
I was.
Fifteen years ago.
No.
Patti
is out there.
Open the door
and you’ll see reality.
Fran!
Where’s Fran?
What have you done to him?
You did it.
You turned him into this.
You’re not Patti!
Fifteen years ago you tricked me
into freeing you from the tree.
You promised you’d leave.
but instead you killed my mother.
No!
And then you possessed my father.
taking advantage
of his weakest moment.
You created a dream world in his mind
in which you’re happy. time doesn’t pass.
everyone adores you...
For fifteen years you controlled his will
so he didn’t want to see anyone
or leave the house.
He merely
subsists.
sleeps.
dreams
of your ideal world.
And all that.
all that is killing him.
you are killing him.
But you don’t realize.
because after all this time
you are trapped in your own fantasy.
in your own obsession.
And really.
you’re not married to him.
and you’re not a world famous artist.
You’re just a parasite.
Your father deserved that.
and a lot more.
But my mother didn’t.
And neither did Janis.
She killed herself five years ago.
Neither she nor he
ever got over my mother’s death.
You know.
it was hard for me to understand
what was happening inside his head.
And even harder to infiltrate the fantasy
in which you’d trapped him.
You’ve grown up a lot. Patti.
Congratulations.
you fooled me very well.
I had a very good teacher.
Thank you.
I don’t mean you.
Why are you here?
To help me transition?
We’ve thought of something better.
Do you like it?
Begoña’s idea.
It wasn’t easy to find this.
Pretty. so pretty. my beautiful Oscar.
Pretty. so pretty. my gentle Oscar.
Fly sweetly.
Fly blue.
Fran. this isn’t happening.
I’m your rose of sugar.
Fran. you’re dreaming.
I’m your rose of honey.
We’re both dreaming.
Look at me.
Dad. that’s it.
It’s over.
Let’s leave here forever.
Let’s leave here.
Fran.
THE HANGED WOMAN